[

url.zip](https://www.url.zip/)

Privacy Policy
--------------

#### Effective Date: April 19, 2023

Welcome to url.zip. This Privacy Policy describes the policies and procedures of url.zip, Inc. (“url.zip”, “we” or “us”) for the collection, use, security and disclosure of personal information about you. It also describes your choices regarding use, access, deletion, and correction of your personal information.

### Scope

This Privacy Policy explains how url.zip treats the personal information it gathers when you use or access https://url.zip (the “Site”) or the services, features, content or applications offered by url.zip (collectively with the Site, the “Services”), or when you view or interact with a url.zip link (either our https://url.zip links or one of our branded domains). This Privacy Policy also covers url.zip’s treatment of any information about you that url.zip’s customers share with url.zip.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to the practices of other businesses that url.zip does not own or control, including other companies’ websites, services and applications (“Third Party Services”) that you can access through the Services or to individuals that url.zip does not manage or employ. We cannot take responsibility for the content or privacy policies of Third Party Services. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of any Third Party Services you access or use.

### Information We Collect

url.zip may collect personal information about you from the following sources, as described in this Privacy Policy, when you (i) register for the Site and the Services, through your user account with url.zip, including registering through a third-party social networking service (your “Account”); (ii) use the Services; or (iii) view or interact with a url.zip link (either our url.zip links or one of our branded domains) on a third-party website. We collect the following types of information from you, some of which might be considered personal information under applicable law.

#### When You Register for a url.zip Account

When you create an Account, we may collect personal information from you, such as your name, phone number, company name, industry, job title, company size, email address, and sign-in information. If you create an Account using your login information from a third-party account, such as Google, Facebook, Apple, or Twitter, we will access and collect the personal information about you that the third-party account provides (which is based on your privacy settings with the third-party account), so that you can log into your Account with us. We use your contact information to send you information about our Services and communicate with you about your Account, your activities on our Site and Services and policy changes. You may unsubscribe from receiving certain types of these messages through your Account settings, although url.zip reserves the right to contact you when we believe it is necessary, such as for administrative and account management purposes.

Some features of the Services allow registered users to provide their own content to the Services, such as written descriptions of URLs, comments, images and video. Unless you request deletion of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy, all content submitted by you to the Services may be retained by url.zip, even after you terminate your Account and may continue to be shared by third parties, as described in this Privacy Policy.

#### When You Create a url.zip Link

One feature of the Services is the ability to create shortened uniform resource locators (URLs) of websites (“url.zip Links” or “shortLinks”). Users can create url.zip Links without registering for an account. When you create a url.zip Link, url.zip collects and stores both the original URL and the shortened URL and, if you are logged in to your Account, we will associate that information with your Account. url.zip also collects and stores your IP address, your geolocation data (which we derive from your IP address), the time and date on which you shortened the original URL, and if you share a url.zip Link on a social networking platform, the name of the platform and your username on that platform.

#### When You Interact With a url.zip Link

url.zip automatically collects personal information about the interaction (such as clicks or views) with every url.zip Link created through the Services (either our url.zip links or one of our branded domains) on a third-party website. This information includes, but is not limited to: (i) the IP address and location derived from the IP address; (ii) internet or other electronic network activity information like the referring websites or services; (iii) the time and date of each access; (iv) device settings, such as browser type, operating system, and language; (v) cookies, as described below, and mobile advertising identiﬁers and (v) information about sharing of the url.zip Link on Third Party Services (collectively, “url.zip Link Metrics”). As described in this policy, we use url.zip Link Metrics to provide the Services, to understand and analyze how our Services are used and to identify trends, and to detect, deter and prevent malicious, fraudulent or unlawful activity. Please see the “Information We May Share” section of this Privacy Policy for a description of how we may share information we collect when you create, view or interact with url.zip Links.

#### Other Information We Automatically Collect

When you visit the Site, we automatically collect (i) your IP address and location derived from the IP address; (ii) internet or other electronic network activity information, like the referring websites or services; (iii) the time and date of each access; (iv) device settings, such as browser type, operating system, and language; and (v) cookie information. This type of data enables us and third parties authorized by us to ﬁgure out how often individuals use parts of the Site so that we can analyze and improve them.

We may receive a conﬁrmation when you open an email from us. We use this conﬁrmation to improve our customer service.

url.zip may use third-party APIs and software development kits (“SDKs”) to provide certain functions in our Services.

#### Third Party Services

Some features of the Services allow you to share your content and url.zip Links through your accounts with Third Party Services such as Twitter. If you choose to connect url.zip to such Third Party Services, we may collect information related to your use of those Third Party Services, such as authentication tokens that allow us to connect to your Third Party Service accounts. We will ask you for permission before you authorize our collection of this information. We will only use that information for the speciﬁc reason for which it was provided to us. We may also collect information about how you are using the Services to interact with those connected Third Party Services. Note that Third Party Services may have the ability to restrict the information that is provided to us based on your privacy settings of that account.

To enable us to infer the location from the IP addresses of computers or devices that visit our website or click, view or interact with url.zip links as described in this policy, we receive IP-derived location information from our third-party service provider. We also receive business contact information of our business customer contacts and prospects from our third party service provider.

#### Cookies and Other Similar Technologies

url.zip and its partners use cookies or similar technologies to analyze trends, administer the website, track users’ movements around the website, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.

Cookies are pieces of text that may be provided to your computer through your web browser when you access a website. Your browser stores cookies in a manner associated with each website you visit. We use cookies to enable our servers to recognize your web browser and tell us how and when you visit our Site and use the Services through the web.

url.zip cookies also allow url.zip to track when you have clicked on a url.zip Link. Each click of a url.zip Link is tracked using a unique identiﬁer assigned to you in one or more cookies stored by your web browser and associated with url.zip. We may associate the unique identiﬁer in our cookies with the other information we automatically collect when you use the Services, as described above, including your IP address, url.zip Links you click, url.zip Links you create, and information with your Account if you have one.

Most browsers have an option for turning off the cookie feature, which will prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, as well as (depending on the sophistication of your browser software) allowing you to decide on acceptance of each new cookie in a variety of ways. If you disable cookies, you will not be able to use some features of the Services. We do not currently recognize do-not-track signals.

We partner with third parties to track utilization and behavior on the Site, and to manage our advertising on other websites. Our third-party partners may use cookies, web beacons, pixel tags or similar technologies in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to opt out of interest-based advertising click here (https://preferences-mgr.trustarc.com/) or if located in the European Union click here (https://www.youronlinechoices.eu/).

This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by url.zip only and does not cover the use of cookies by any Third Party Services. url.zip does not control when or how third parties place cookies on your computer, such as when you visit a website through a url.zip Link. You can manage other companies’ cookies used for online advertising by visiting the Digital Advertising Alliance’s Consumer Choice Page (http://www.aboutads.info/choices/).

### How We Use Information

We use the personal information we collect for a variety of administrative and business purposes to:

* operate our Site and provide the Services, process and complete any transactions, verify individual identity,
* respond to inquiries, questions and comments and provide customer and technical support, provide access to certain functionalities of our Services,
* personalize and improve the Services and develop new products and services,
* communicate with our current and prospective customers concerning our services, measure interest and engagement in our Site and Services,
* monitor and analyze usage and trends of the Site and Services,
* provide services to our customers to allow them to understand how you interact with our Services and to help detect, deter and prevent malicious, fraudulent or unlawful activity,
* comply with any legal obligations, and
* enforce our terms and as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy.

#### Usage Across Devices

We may use the information we collect to make inferences that a unique individual has created or interacted with url.zip links on different devices so that we can detect, deter and prevent malicious, fraudulent or unlawful activity and analyze how users use our Services. For example, if you created a url.zip link on a computer connected to your residential WiFi network, and you soon thereafter clicked on a url.zip link on a mobile device connected to the same WiFi network, we may infer that a single individual created and clicked on the url.zip links because both events were associated with the same IP address in the same time period.

### Information We Share

The Services are designed to help you share information with others. In addition, we provide Services to our Customers that use url.zip Link Metrics. As a result, the following categories of personal information generated through your use of the Services are shared publicly or with the following categories of third parties for the business purposes described below.

#### url.zip Links You Create

Much of your activity on and through the Services is public by default. For example, when you create a url.zip Link, the original URLs you have shortened and the corresponding url.zip Links are publicly available.

#### Account Information

Where permitted by law, if you register a url.zip Account with an email address on a domain owned by an organization, (for example, an employer or educational institution where you have an email account), we may share your email address and information about your Account, such as the number of links you have created, with that organization to explore the organization’s interest in creating or managing an enterprise account or for related purposes.

#### Information Shared with Service Providers

We may employ and contract with third parties to perform certain tasks on our behalf and under our direction (our “Service Providers”). We may need to share information about you with our Service Providers in order to fulfill certain business purposes, like providing our product with research and analytics on user behavior and providing advertising products and services to users, processing payments, and providing email marketing and support services. Our agreements with these Service Providers authorize them to use your information only as necessary to provide services to us. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by our agreements with our service providers.

#### Information Disclosed for the Protection of url.zip and Others

url.zip may access, read, preserve, and disclose any information it collects when it has a good faith belief that doing so is reasonably necessary to (i) comply with a law, regulation, or compulsory legal request, including process from a governmental law enforcement or national security agency, (ii) enforce the Privacy Policy or Terms of Service, including investigation of potential violations hereof, (iii) detect, deter, prevent or otherwise address malicious, fraudulent or unlawful activity, (iv) respond to user support requests, or (v) protect the rights, property or safety of url.zip, its users and the public. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for protection from malicious, fraudulent or unlawful activity.

### INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS

Depending on your location, information about you may be transferred to the United States or other countries outside the EU or European Economic Area (EEA) or may be processed there. These data transfers are necessary to provide you with the services outlined in this policy.

To protect your personal data, we rely on appropriate legal basis for each data transfer. In particular, we use contractual safeguards such as Standard Contractual Clauses approved by the European Commission. Where applicable, we base data transfers also on adequacy decisions issued by the European Commission.

Please feel free to contact us for further information about international data transfers.

### Retention

We retain the personal information we receive as described in this Privacy Policy for as long as you use our Services or as necessary to fulﬁll the purpose(s) for which it was collected, provide our Services, resolve disputes, establish legal defenses, conduct audits, pursue legitimate business purposes, enforce our agreements, and comply with applicable legal obligations.

### Information Security

Your Account information is protected by a password for your privacy and security. You can help prevent unauthorized access to your Account by selecting and protecting your password appropriately, making use of two-factor authentication, and limiting access to your computer and browser by signing off after you have ﬁnished accessing your Account.

url.zip endeavors to protect the information it collects about its users using reasonable security processes and controls, however, despite these efforts, no security measure is perfect or impenetrable and url.zip does not guarantee or warrant that such measures will prevent unauthorized access to the information about you that is stored by url.zip. In the event we experience a breach of security, we will promptly notify you if your personal information has been compromised, in accordance with applicable law.

### Choice and Access

You don’t need an Account to create url.zip Links, and you can use many of the features of the Services without registering, thereby limiting the type of information that is collected about you individually. If you have a url.zip Account, you may access, correct, or request deletion of your personal information by logging into your Account. Once logged in to your account, you will be able to view a history of the URLs you have shortened and the metrics pages for those URLs. You can request a complete copy of the personal information we store about your account by clicking the button to request a report in your Account Settings.

You can delete your Account at any time through your Account settings page. If you delete your Account, you will no longer be able to access or use the Services. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe. If you are a resident of the EEA or Switzerland, you have the right to ask that your personal data be corrected, updated, or erased. Additionally, you may have the right to access your personal data and receive a copy of your personal data undergoing processing. You may also have the right to object to, or request that we restrict, certain processing.

For all other requests to exercise any of your rights, you may contact us as indicated in the “Questions” section below. Once we receive your request, we will ask that you verify your identity such as by authenticating through your account. If you do not have a url.zip account, url.zip has no way of identifying you or verifying that you created or clicked on a url.zip link.

You may be entitled, in accordance with applicable law, to submit a request through an authorized agent. To designate an authorized agent to exercise your rights and choices on your behalf, please provide a written attestation, declaration, or permission that has either been physically signed or provided electronically per applicable law. In certain circumstances, we may be required by law to retain your personal information.

Please note that in the interest of ensuring that existing url.zip Links continue to function for all of our users, the url.zip Links that you have created and shared cannot be deleted or disabled (even if your Account is deleted), and any shortening and sharing activity that has already occurred on your Account also cannot be deleted. If you have concerns about any unauthorized use of your Account, you can delete your account within your Account settings.

Please see the Cookies section above for additional choices you may have.

### California Residents

If you are a California Resident, you may request, subject to any applicable exceptions, access to and deletion of your information or more information about how we collect, use, and disclose personal information. You may submit a verifiable request to know and exercise any of your other rights as described in the “Choice and Access” section above. We will not discriminate against you for exercising your rights and choices.

The categories of personal information that we have collected in the preceding 12 months and their sources are provided in the “Information We Collect” section above. Our business purposes for collecting personal information are described in the “How We Use Information” section above.

url.zip does not sell your personal information to third parties for money or other valuable consideration. url.zip does permit third parties to collect the information described above through our Service and discloses such information with third parties for business purposes as described in this Privacy Policy, including but not limited to providing advertising on our Service and elsewhere based on users’ online activities over time and across different sites, services, and devices. The categories of third parties to whom we disclose personal information are provided in the “Information We Share” section above.

### Supervisory Authority

If you are located in the European Economic Area, you have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority if you believe our Processing of your Personal Information violates applicable law.

### Changes to This Privacy Policy

url.zip may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we make material changes in the way we collect or use information, we will notify you by posting an announcement on the Services or sending you an email, and we will indicate when those changes will become effective. You are agreeing to be bound by any changes to the Privacy Policy when you use the Services after those changes become effective.

🇺🇸 English

Made with ❤️ by developers from Colombia 👩🏻‍💻👨🏼‍💻

© 2023 khriztianmoreno.dev - All rights reserved.
